Bola Olaniyan

UX/UI designer

Check my portfolio

I am a designer with over 2 years of experience in UX/ UI design. I have experience working remotely with small startup teams and clients on projects that cuts across fields such as Fintech, Education, Social media, E-commerce and even Artificial Intelligence.

bolaolaniyanadedayo@gmail.com

+2349037762772

Work experiences

UI/UX Designer - Cyclebreeze R &D

January. 2022 - Aug 2022 @ Ogbomosho, Nigeria(Hybrid)

- Coordinated with other divisions across the company, including project management and development team in developing new initiatives, products, and services herein increasing company value by 30%.
- Designed a fin-tech project to improve and consolidate thrift and group saving; optimized communication flow among 4 departments and cut down paperwork by 75%
- Maintained constant and healthy communication with the stakeholders and every involved team across the company resulting in a 60% increase in productivity.

UI/UX Designer - The House Interior LLC

Jun. 2022 @ Georgia, United States(Remote)

- Collaborated with the design lead to tailor a refined design system for the platform increasing uniformity by over 70%.
- Liaised with the developers to consolidate the designed flows and upgrade the overall user experience by 40%.

UI/UX Designer - Century Leap

Oct. 2020 - Apr. 2022 @ Ilorin, Nigeria(Hybrid)

- Concerted with different teams across the company to build a platform that enables users to keep their card details safe on their devices.
- Revamped the aforementioned platform to work offline only to strengthen user safety and reduce card loss by 40%
- Planned and executed user research with a team of three other designers on crypto traders and enthusiasts.
- Conceptualized and implemented a platform that enabled users to keep tabs on the rise and fall of their favorite cryptocurrency assets, hereby reducing asset loss by 35%.

Intern UI/UX Designer - With Ozenua Oluwatobi

Oct. 2019 - April 2020 @ Ilorin, Nigeria(Hybrid)

- Learned the basics of UIUX I didn't understand when I was learning
- Collaborated with the 2 other designers including the lead designer on a project in the fintech space
 Lwas assigned to design a fintech landing page
- I was assigned to design a fintech landing page from scratch to finish.

Education & certificates

BSc Computer Science - Unilorin

Nov. 2018 - Nov. 2022 @ Ilorin, Nigeria

 I was the assistant class lead for my class and I helped coordinate and cater for the needs of my coursemates.

Volunteering

fuller resume

Lead UI/UX Designer - Evon Al

Apr. 2022 - Present @ Ilorin, Nigeria(Remote)

- Prepared the design system for the company designs, increasing design uniformity by over 80%
- Designed the landing page for the organization.

Skills

User research
Information architecture
Wireframing
Sketching
High-fidelity prototyping
Design thinking

Tools

Figma
Whimsical
Zeplin
Adobe Photoshop
Webflow
Notion

Languages

Yoruba native English fluent

Strengths

Good communication
Honest & transparent
Highly enthusiastic
Managing time
Asking for help

Favorite books

Steal like an Artist Ego is the Enemy Keep Going Show your work

Thanks for taking the time to read my resumé. Be sure to

contact me if you have any

questions or you would like a

→ +234907

→ bolaolaniyanadedayo@gmail.com

Check my portfolio